Macbeth Gallery Scrapbooks
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Scrapbooks, 1892-1952, Series 5:; (Box 120-130; 3.3 linear feet)
  - Scrapbook 20, 1949-1952 (Reel NMC4, Frame 332-400)
Apr. 10-30, 1935 After St. Ives by Hayley Lever (NMc3: 761-762)
date unknown Mr. Jonas Lie: Brittany and Other Recent Paintings (NMc3: 764)
Sept. 30-Oct. 7, 1930 Watercolors by Carolyn G. Bradley and Marion L. Simmons (NMc3: 764-765)
March 28-April 19, 1932 Small Paintings of Museum Importance on Exhibition (NM3: 764-767)
Scrapbook 16, February 1935-January 1938
Date Exhibition
Feb. 5-19, 1935 Robert Strong Woodward, "Landscapes of New England" (NMc4: 401-402)
Feb. 19-28, 1935 Portraits by Leonebel Jacobs (NMc4: 404)
Mar. 5-18, 1935 Loan Exhibition (NMc4: 408-409)
Apr. 23-May 13, 1935 Still Lifes by Emil Carlsen, 1853-1932 (NMc4: 411-413)
May 14-June 3, 1935 Watercolors and Pastels (NMc4: 414)
Summer 1935 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 415)
Oct. 8-21, 1935 Recent Paintings by Frederick C. Frieseke (NMc4: 416-417)
Nov. 19-Dec. 3, 1935 Drawings by Lintott (NMc4: 418-419)
Dec. 3-31, 1935 Drawings and Lithographs by Stow Wengenroth (NMc4: 420)
Dec. 9-31, 1935 Oils, Watercolors, Drawings by Gertude Schweitzer (NMc4: 421)
Jan. 14-Feb. 3, 1936 Herbert Meyer (NMc4: 422-423)
Feb. 1936 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 429)
Feb. 1936 Drawings by Eastman Johnson (NMc4: 430)
Feb. 4-17, 1936 Homer D. Martin, 1836-1897, Centennial Exhibition (NMc4: 426-427)
Mar. 10-23, 1936 Contemporary Americans (NMc: 430)
Mar. 10-23, 1936 Watercolors by Steven Donahos (NMc4: 430)
Mar. 24-Apr. 16, 1936 Brackman (NMc4: 431)
Apr. 7-27, 1936 Paintings and Watercolors by C. K. Chatterton (NMc4: 433-434)
Apr. 28-May 11, 1936 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 435)
Apr. 28-May 11, 1936 Watercolors by Mary S. Powers (NMc4: 435)
May 19-June 1, 1936 Drawings by Richard Guggenheimer (NMc4: 436)
May 27-June 3, 1936 Pastel Portraits by Frank Root McCreery (NMc4: 437-438)
Oct. 5-26, 1936 Opening Exhibition, 45th Season, New Paintings by Fourteen American Painters (NMc4: 447-448)
Nov. 4-16 1936 Paintings by Elliot Orr (NMc4: 444-445)
Nov. 17-30, 1936 Recent Paintings by Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 447-448)
Dec. 1936 Lester D. Boronda: Paintings from Mason's Island (NMc4: 449)
Dec. 15, 1936-Jan. 18, 1937 An Introduction to Homer (NMc4: 451-460)
Jan. 19-Feb. 1, 1937 Exhibition of Portraits by Stuart, Copley, West, Allston, Badger, Jarvis, Morse, Sully, Peale, Smibert and Waldo (NMc4: 478-479)
Jan. 19-Feb. 1, 1937 Group of Watercolors (NMc4: 480)
Feb. 2-15, 1937 John C. E. Taylor: Flower Arrangements and Other Oils (NMc4: 481)
Feb. 16-Mar. 1, 1937 Paintings and Watercolors by Horace Day (NMc4: 482)
Mar. 2-15, 1937 Hayley Lever, Paintings New and Old (NMc4: 485)
Mar. 2-15, 1937 Paintings by Josef Presser (NMc4: 485)
Mar. 16-Apr. 5, 1937 Recent Work by Jon Corbino (NMc4: 487-490)
Apr. 13-26, 1937 Memorial Exhibition of Paintings, Crayon Drawings and Dry Points by the late Alexander Shilling (NMc4: 499)
Apr. 30-May 17, 1937 Edna Reindel (NMc4: 503)
Oct. 5-19, 1937 American Paintings Dedicating the Art Gallery Woman's Club Art Building, Montana State University (NMc4: 505-514)
Oct. 6-18, 1937 Opening Exhibition, Paintings by a Group of Contemporary Artists (NMc4: 517)
Oct. 19-Nov. 1, 1937 First Exhibition, Watercolors by Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 518-519)
Nov. 2-15, 1937 Marine and Other Subjects from the Canary Islands by Cadwallader Washburn (NMc4: 524-525)
Nov. 16-29, 1937 Paintings by Lorenzo James Hatch (NMc4: 524-525)
Nov. 30-Dec. 14, 1937 Monhegan Island, Maine, Marines by Jay Connaway (NMc4: 527)
Jan. 4-17, 1938 "The Eight" Thirty Years Later (NMc4: 529-530)
Scrapbook 17, January 1938-July 1941
Date Exhibition
Jan. 18-Feb. 1, 1938 Paintings by Dale Nichols (NMc4: 538-540)
Feb. 8-21, 1938 Vermont in Watercolors by Stanford Stevens (NMc4: 541-542)
Feb. 8-21, 1938 Modern American Interior: Prizewinning Design and Selected Drawings from a Competition Sponsored by James H. Blauvet and Associates, Interior Designers (NMc4: 543)
Feb. 23-Mar. 7, 1938 Herbert Dickens Ryman (NMc4: 546)
Mar. 1-14, 1938 Paintings and Watercolors by Anne Goldthwaite (NMc4: 546-547)
Mar. 8-21, 1938 Recent Watercolors of Woodstock, Charleston, New England by John W. Taylor (NMc4: 548-549)
Mar. 22-Apr. 11, 1938 Jon Corbino (NMc4: 554-561)
Apr. 12-25, 1938 Paintings by Ohio Artists (NMc4: 580-571)
Apr. 26-May 9, 1938 Paintings by Furman Joseph Finck (NMc4: 572-573)
May-June 1938 Winslow Homer: Watercolors and Early Oils from the Estate of Mrs. Charles S. Homer and Other Sources (NMc4: 574-579)
Oct. 4-28, 1938 Opening Exhibition (NMc4: 581)
Nov. 1-23, 1938 Dale Nichols, Watercolors and Tempera of Alaskan Subjects (NMc4: 582-583)
Nov. 29-Dec. 19, 1938 Sea Island Country Watercolors by Horace Day (NMc4: 584)
Jan. 10-30, 1939 Herbert Meyer (NMc4: 588-589)
Feb. 7-27, 1939 American Watercolors Past and Present (NMc4: 592-597
Mar. 7-Apr. 3, 1939 Monhegan by Jay Connaway (NMc4: 602-603)
Apr. 5-24, 1919 Oils and Watercolors by Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 606-607)
May 2-22, 1939 Paintings by Francis Chapin, Antonio P. Matino, and Moses Soyer and Drawings by Jon Corbino (NMc4: 609-611)
Oct. 10-30, 1939 Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 614)
Nov. 1-30, 1939 Americana Paintings, Watercolors, Prints, Drawings (NMc4: 616-617)
Dec. 5-30, 1939 In the Georges Islands, Maine: Paintings by N.C. Wyeth (NMc4: 618)
Dec. 5-30, 1939 Dry Brush Drawings by Stow Wengenroth (NMc4: 618-619)
Jan. 2-27, 1940 Brackman (NMc4: 623-624)
Jan. 30-Feb. 19, 1940 Paintings by Moses Soyer (NMc4: 630-631)
Feb. 20-Mar. 11, 1940 Watercolors by Emil J. Kosa, Jr. (NMc4: 637)
Mar. 12-30, 1940 Paintings by Edna Reindel (NMc4: 636)
April 1940 Paintings and Drawings by Jon Corbino (NMc4: 639-640)
May 7-18, 1940 "Star Boat Races," by Gerald Foster (NMc4: 640)
Summer 1940 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 641)
Oct. 1940 October Exhibition (NMc4: 642)
Nov. 12-Dec. 2, 1940 Paintings by Antonio P. Martino (NMc4: 645)
Dec. 10-30, 1940 Monhegan Paintings and Sketches by Jay Connaway (NMc4: 648)
Dec. 31, 1940-Jan. 13, 1941 Oils and Watercolors by Contemporary Artists (NMc4: 649)
Jan. 14-Feb. 3, 1941 Paintings and Drawings by Augustus Vincent Tack (NMc4: 650-651)
Feb. 4-24, 1941 Recent Paintings by Peter Hurd (NMc4: 652)
Feb. 18-Mar. 3, 1941 Earl Gross Watercolors (NMc4: 654-655)
Feb. 25-Mar. 16, 1941 Recent Paintings by Herman Maril (NMc4: 656-657)
Mar. 18-Apr. 5, 1941 Joseph de Martini Gouache Paintings (NMc4: 656)
Mar. 25-Apr. 7, 1941 Men of Moment: Drawings by Ivan Opffer (NMc4: 660)
Apr. 8-28, 1941 Paintings by Orland Campbell (NMc4: 661-662)
Apr. 29-May 12, 1941 Small Paintings by Moses Soyer (NMc4: 667-668)
May 1941 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 667)
May 13-24, 1941 The 1941 Showing of Blauvelt Interiors (NMc4: 669-671)
May-June 1941 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 669)
Scrapbook 18, July 1941-October 1945
Date Exhibition
Sept. 1941 Group Exhibition: Oils (NMc4: 682)
Oct. 7-27, 1941 Third Exhibition of Watercolors by Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 685)
Oct. 28-Nov. 17, 1941 Recent Oils and Watercolors by Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 685-686)
Oct. 28-Nov. 17, 1941 Watercolors by Merrill A. Bailey (NMc4: 685)
Nov. 18-Dec. 1, 1941 Drawings and Watercolors by Carl Newland Werntz (NMc4: 688-689)
Nov. 18-Dec. 1, 1941 Hymn to the Sun: A Sculpture in Bronze by Emily Winthrop Miles (NMc4: 688)
Dec. 1941 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 690)
Dec. 2-22, 1941 Original Dolls by Edith Flack Ackley and their Portraits in Watercolor by Telka Ackley (NMc4: 690)
Jan. 5-24, 1942 Paintings by Furman Joseph Finck (NMc4: 694)
Jan. 5-24, 1942 Watercolors of Maine and Florida by Maurice Becker (NMc4: 694-695)
Jan. 19-Feb. 14, 1942 Watercolors, Pastels, Drawings by Jerome Myers, 1867-1940 (NMc4: 696)
Feb. 16-28, 1942 Watercolors by Cory Kilvert (NMc4: 697-698)
Feb. 16-Mar. 7, 1942 Paintings by Deceased American Masters (NMc4: 697-698)
Mar. 9-28, 1942 Paintings by Marsden Hartley (NMc4: 700-701)
Mar. 9-28, 1942 Watercolors by Karl Mattern (NMc4: 700)
Apr. 13-30, 1942 Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition, 1892-1942 (NMc4: 703-704)
May 4-29, 1942 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 707)
June 1942 June Exhibition (NMc4: 708)
June 15-27, 1942 War Bond Exhibitions of Contemporary American Art (NMc4: 708)
Sept. 1942 September Exhibition (NMc4: 709)
Nov. 16-28, 1942 Watercolors by Jean Paul Slusser (NMc4: 710)
Nov. 24-Dec. 12, 1942 T. Chambers, First American Modern (NMc4: 711-714)
Dec. 1-14, 1942 Watercolors by Red Robin (NMc4: 715-716)
Dec. 15, 1942-Jan. 2, 1943 Leaves From a Soldier's Sketchbook by Pvt. Olin Dows, U. S. Army (NMc4: 717)
Jan. 4-23, 1943 Paintings by Sprinchorn (NMc4: 717-718)
Feb. 1-13, 1943 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 719)
Feb. 15-Mar. 6, 1943 Small Paintings by Moses Soyer (NMc4: 720)
Mar. 15-27, 1943 Ellen du Pont Wheelwright (NMc4: 721)
Mar. 15-27, 1943 Watercolors by Cory Kilvert (NMc4: 721)
Mar. 29-Apr. 17, 1943 Recent Paintings by Joseph De Martini (NMc4: 722)
Mar. 29-Apr. 17, 1943 Watercolor Exhibition (NMc4: 722)
Apr. 19-May 1, 1943 Corp. Herman Maril (NMc4: 728)
Apr. 19-May 8, 1943 Theodore Robinson (NMc4: 723-725)
May-June 1943 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 729)
Sept. 1943 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 731)
Oct. 11-30, 1943 Watercolors by Henry Gasser (NMc4: 723-733)
Nov. 1-20, 1943 Tempera and Watercolors by Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 735-736)
Nov. 22-Dec. 4, 1943 Portraits of Children by Barnard Lentott (NMc4: 741-742)
Dec. 1943 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 741)
Dec. 6-24, 1943 Rural Vermont: Watercolors by Sylvia Wright (NMc4: 743-744)
Jan. 3-15, 1944 Watercolors of War by Red Robin (NMc4: 743-744)
Jan. 31-Feb. 19, 1944 Loan Exhibition, Worthington Whittredge, 1825-1910 (NMc4: 745-746)
Feb. 21-Mar. 11, 1944 Paintings by Constance Richardson (NMc4: 749-750)
Mar. 13-Apr. 1, 1944 Watercolors by Vanessa Helder (NMc4: 751, 753)
Mar. 13-Apr. 1, 1944 Temperas and Watercolors by Peter Hurd (NMc4: 751-753)
Apr. 3-22, 1944 American Paintings of the Early 19th Century (NMc4: 754-755)
Apr. 24-May 13, 1944 Brackman (NMc4: 756-757)
May 15-June 3, 1944 Two Vermont Artists: Clay Bartlett and Arthur K. D. Healy (NMc4: 758-759)
June 5-24, 1944 Women at War by Edna Reindel (NMc4: 760)
July 1944 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 762)
Sept. 25-Oct. 15, 1944 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 763)
Oct. 16-Nov. 4, 1944 Paintings by Felicia Meyer (NMc4: 764-765)
Nov. 15-Dec. 2, 1944 The Aleutian Air Force: Paintings by Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 766-767)
Dec. 4-23, 1944 Paintings by John W. Taylor (NMc4: 769-770)
Jan. 8-27, 1945 Paintings by Carl Gaertner (NMc4: 771-772)
Jan. 29-Feb. 10, 1945 Contemporary American Watercolors (NMc4: 772)
Feb. 19-Mar. 10, 1945 Paintings and Watercolors by Maurice Becker (NMc4: 773-774)
Mar. 12-31, 1945 Some Early 19th Century Americans (NMc4: 777-778)
Apr. 2-21, 1945 Paintings by Joseph De Martini (NMc4: 778-779)
Apr. 23-May 12, 1945 Gouaches by Herman Maril (NMc4: 781)
Apr. 23-May 12, 1945 Paintings by Molly Luce (NMc4: 781-782)
May-June 1945 Group Exhibition: Contemporary Oils and Watercolors (NMc4: 783)
July, Sept., 1945 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 783)
Oct. 1-7, 1945 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 784)
Scrapbook 19, October 1945-November 1949
Date Exhibition
Oct. 26-Nov. 17, 1945 Tempera and Watercolors by Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 787-788)
Nov. 26-Dec. 15, 1945 Marsden Hartley: Paintings and Drawings (NMc4: 791-792)
Dec. 1945 Christmas Exhibition (NMc4: 793)
Jan. 7-26, 1946 New York in Watercolors by James Lechay (NMc4: 794)
Jan. 28-Feb. 16, 1946 Herbert Meyer (NMc4: 795)
Feb. 18-Mar. 19, 1946 Ary Stillman (NMc4: 797-798)
Mar. 11-30, 1946 Watercolors by Arthur K. D. Haley (NMc4: 800-801)
Apr. 1-20, 1946 Albert P. Ryder (NMc4: 802-805)
Apr. 22-May 11, 1946 Paintings by Constance Richardson (NMc4: 809-810)
May 13-31, 1946 Furman Jospeh Finck (NMc4: 811-812)
June 1946 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 813)
July 1946 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 813)
Sept. 1946 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 814)
Sept. 30-Oct. 19, 1946 Gouaches by Charles Schucker (NMc4: 815)
Oct. 2-Nov. 9, 1946 Watercolors and Drawings by Olin Dows (NMc4: 816-817)
Nov. 4-30, 1946 Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 818)
Dec. 2-28, 1946 Oils and Watercolors by Emil J. Kosa, Jr. (NMc4: 819-820)
Jan. 6-26, 1947 Carl Gaertner (NMc4: 821-822)
Jan. 27-Feb. 15, 1947 Carl Sprinchorn (NMc4: 823)
Mar. 3-22, 1947 Dorothy Hoyt (NMc4: 825-826)
Mar. 24-Apr. 12, 1947 Joseph De Martini (NMc4: 827-828)
Apr. 14-May 10, 1947 Whistler Loan Exhibition (NMc4: 828-834)
June-July, 1947 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 840)
Sept. 1947 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 841)
Oct. 13-Nov. 1, 1947 Paintings by Allen Tucker (NMc4: 842-844)
Nov. 3-22, 1947 Watercolors by Henry Gasser (NMc4: 846-847)
Nov. 24-Dec. 13, 1947 James Lechay (NMc4: 849-850)
Dec. 15, 1947-Jan. 3, 1948 Watercolor Exhibition (NMc4: 851)
Jan. 5-24, 1948 Clay Bartlett (NMc4: 852-853)
Jan. 26-Feb. 14, 1945 Exhibition (NMc4: 854)
Jan. 26-Feb. 14, 1948 Oils and Watercolors by Contemporary Artists (NMc4: 854)
Feb. 16-Mar. 6, 1948 Herman Maril (NMc4: 855-856)
Mar. 22-Apr. 3, 1948 American Art: A Multiple Exhibition arranged by the Associated Dealers in American Art (NMc4: 857-858)
Apr. 5-24, 1948 Raphael Gleitsmann (NMc4: 866-867)
Apr. 26-May 15, 1948 Oils and Watercolors by John La Farge (NMc4: 864)
May-Sept. 1948 Group Exhibitions (NMc4: 867)
Oct. 4-23, 1948 Watercolors by Charles Culver (NMc4: 869-870)
Oct. 26-Nov. 13, 1948 Ogden M. Pleissner (NMc4: 872)
Nov. 15-Dec. 4, 1948 Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 874-875)
Nov. 21-Dec. 4, 1948 Oils and Gouaches by Charles Schucker (NMc4: 332-333)
Dec. 6-31, 1948 Watercolors and Drawings by Hermann Gross (NMc4: 877-878)
Jan. 4-22, 1949 Electra Bostwick (NMc4: 879, 882)
Jan. 27-Feb. 19, 1949 Paintings by Edna Reindel (NMc4: 880-881)
Feb. 28-Mar. 19, 1949 Thomas Doughty (NMc4: 885-887)
Mar. 21-Apr. 9, 1949 Watercolors by Arthur K. D. Healy (NMc4: 889)
Apr. 12-30, 1949 Drawings by Olin Dows (NMc4: 890)
May 1949 Group Exhibition (NMc4: 894)
Oct. 10-29, 1949 Clay Bartlett: Paintings of North and South America (NMc4: 895-896)
Nov. 1-19, 1949 Watercolors by Henry Gasser (NMc4: 897-898)
Scrapbook 20, 1949-1952
Date Exhibition
Nov. 21-Dec. 10, 1949 Oils and Gouaches by Charles Shucker (NMc4: 332-333)
Dec. 1949 Watercolor Exhibition (NMc4: 334)
Jan. 3-21, 1950 Carl Gaertner (NMc4: 335-356)
Jan. 23-Feb. 11, 1950 Constance Richardson (NMc4: 337-338)
Mar. 6-25, 1950 John Taylor (NMc4: 339-340)
Apr. 1950 Joseph De Martini (NMc4: 341)
May 8-27, 1950 Carl Sprinchorn (NMc4: 342-343)
Summer 1950 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 345)
Oct. 9-28, 1950 Caseins by James Lechay (NMc4: 345-346)
Oct. 31-Nov. 18, 1950 Ogden M. Pleissner: Paris and the Provinces (NMc4: 347-348)
Nov. 21-Dec. 9, 1950 Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 349-350)
Jan. 2-20, 1951 Nat Koffman (NMc4: 356-357)
Jan. 22-Feb. 10, 1951 Watercolors by Hermann Gross (NMc4: 358)
Feb. 12-Mar. 3, 1951 Watercolors (D55:390-391; NMc4: 359)
Mar. 5-24, 1951 Paintings by Francis Colburn (NMc4: 360)
Mar. 27-Apr. 14, 1951 Paintings by Herman Maril (NMc4: 361)
Apr. 16-May 5, 1951 Raphael Gleitsmann (NMc4: 362-363)
Summer 1951 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 364)
July 7-Aug. 4, 1951 Paintings and Drawings by Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 364-381)
Nov. 26-Dec. 15, 1951 Watercolors by Arthur K. D. Healy (NMc4: 387)
Feb. 4-Mar. 1, 1952 Italian Landscapes by George Inness (NMc4: 388-389)
June-July, Sept. 1952 Summer Exhibition (NMc4: 392)
Nov. 6-29, 1952 Andrew Wyeth (NMc4: 391-392)